Well, how fabulous is that?
정말 멋지지 않아요?
I hope that you are as wowed as I am by our new airline, I assistant and everything it can do.
우리 새 항공사, 아이 어시스턴트와 그 모든 것에 저만큼 놀라셨길 바라요
I've taken another screenshot here of of a conversation I'd had, and you can see again that gorgeous
제가 나눈 대화를 스크린샷으로 찍어 봤어요 런던의 아름다운 모습을 다시 한번
image of London.
볼 수 있죠
A very different approach now.
지금은 아주 다른 접근법이죠
Not the montage, but something rather rather simpler.
몽타주보다는 좀 더 간단한 거요
Uh, it I find it astounding that you get such variety, such diversity of images.
이렇게 다양하고 다양한 이미지를 볼 수 있다니 놀라워요 Get it
Um, and I also find it astounding that it's so easy to put together these sophisticated frameworks
또 하나 놀라운 건 이렇게 정교한 프레임워크를 조립하기가 이렇게 쉽다는 거예요 많은 기능성 요소를
involving lots of functionality.
포함해서요 TFI, TFI
Remember, we also had our tool running there, looking up the prices.
그리고 가격표를 보기 위해 툴을 실행시켰죠
Uh, everything we had together was a very sophisticated, complex app, complete with user interface.
우리가 함께 만든 모든 건 사용자 인터페이스가 있는 아주 정교하고 복잡한 앱이었어요
And we did it all just in a few hours worth of work.
그 모든 걸 몇 시간 만에 해냈죠
So it's a congratulations.
축하의 의미군요
But as always, there's a challenge for you and if I may say, one more time, the best way to learn
하지만 늘 그렇듯 도전은 있어요 다시 한번 말하지만 가장 좋은 방법은 직접 해 보는
is by doing.
거예요
It is incredibly important that you now go and do some exercises and work on this to improve it.
이제 여러분이 이 문제를 개선하기 위해 운동하고 노력해야 해요
It's also a lot of fun as an extra bonus.
보너스로 재미도 쏠쏠하죠
So here are some of the things you can do.
여러분이 할 수 있는 걸 알려드리죠
We talked before about adding in another tool to make a booking.
예약을 위한 다른 도구를 추가하는 것에 대해 전에 얘기했었죠
In theory, not obviously a real booking, but make a booking and then it should print to an output
이론상으로는 진짜 예약은 아니지만 예약을 하고 나면 예약이 된 출력물로
that a booking has been made.
프린트되어야 하죠
Or maybe if you if you want, you could have it write to a file or something like that to give you a
원한다면 파일에 작성하게 할 수도 있어요 예약이 됐다는
sense that the booking has happened.
느낌을 주는 거죠
Add that as a tool.
도구로 추가하세요
Hopefully you've done it already, but if not, now's a good time to do it.
이미 해보셨길 바라지만 아니라면 지금이 좋은 때예요
Then add another agent.
그럼 에이전트를 추가해요
Uh, have an agent that is able to translate all of the responses to a different language.
모든 응답을 다른 언어로 번역할 요원이 필요해요
Uh, something that we'd suggested for a previous project.
전에 했던 프로젝트에서 제안했던 거예요
But do that and then show it on the right hand side and use a different frontier model.
하지만 그렇게 하고 오른쪽에 다른 프론티어 모델을 사용하세요
How about Claude, for example, use Claude as a way to translate to another language of your choosing,
예를 들어 클로드를 이용해서 원하는 다른 언어로 통역해 보세요 그리고 라디오
and then you'd have to do some radio work to add another panel.
작업을 해서 패널을 하나 더 추가하고요
With that translation.
그 말을 번역하면요
There will be a little bit of futzing around with Gradio when you do that.
그러면서도 그라디오의 비트를 약간 손봐야 해요
So you may you may find that that requires a little bit of googling, but hopefully you'll get an idea
구글링으로 검색해봐야 알 수 있을 거예요 비트가 떠오르면 구글링할 필요
or you don't need to Google.
없어요
You could actually ask, uh, Claude yourself for some advice on how to extend that Gradio app to add
클로드한테 조언을 구할 수도 있어요 그래디오 앱을 확장해서 번역된
in that extra section to reflect the translation that it makes into another language.
내용을 다른 언어로 반영할 추가 섹션에 추가할 방법요
You'll find that when you do something like that, you provide a bunch of code and ask it to extend
이런 작업을 할 때는 코드를 잔뜩 제공하고 확장하고, 더
it, to do more, to add more capabilities, that these models are excellent at that kind of, uh,
하고, 더 많은 기능을 추가하라고 요청하죠 이런 모델은 그런 종류의 코드에서의 반복에
that kind of iterating on code.
아주 뛰어나요
And then finally, since we've been enjoying multi-modality, one more multimodal task for you is audio
끝으로, 다중 모듈을 즐기고 계시니 한 가지 더 다중 모듈 작업은 오디오 투 텍스트입니다
to text, uh, add an agent that can listen to audio from your audio input source and turn it into text
에이전트를 추가해 오디오 입력 소스에서 오디오를 듣고 인공지능 보조의 입력으로
as the input to the AI assistant.
텍스트로 바꾸는 거죠
And then you've really completed the loop.
그럼 루프가 완성되는 거죠
You'll be able to talk to it, and it will be able to talk back and draw images.
대화도 할 수 있고 대화도 하고 그림도 그릴 수 있죠
When you were looking to ask for ticket prices.
티켓 가격을 물어보려고 할 때요
And that will then complete the week two challenge.
그러면 둘째 주 과제가 끝나요
And at that point you will be very familiar with Multi-modality and with using these, uh, stitching
그때쯤이면 더 큰 작업을 수행하기 위해 서로 다른 요소들을 꿰매는
together these different agents to carry out a bigger task.
다중 양식에 익숙해지겠죠
And at that point, May I tell you?
그 시점에서, 말해도 될까요?
You are now 25% of the way to mastering LM engineering.
이제 달 착륙 엔지니어링의 25%를 완성했어요
25% of the way.
25%는 성공했죠
A quarter of the way through.
4분의 1이 지났어요
You can describe Transformers comfortably, including all of the terminology.
트랜스포머를 편하게 묘사할 수 있어요 모든 용어도 포함해서요
You can code against the APIs, and you can build multimodal assistance using UIs, using tools, using
API에 대해 코드도 할 수 있고 UI, 도구, 에이전트를 이용해 다중 모듈 보조를 구축할 수도
agents.
있어요
This is practically second nature to you at this point.
이젠 이런 게 당신에겐 제2의 천성이군요
Uh.
네
Next week, change in topic to something that is absolutely wonderful the thriving open source community
다음 주엔 정말 멋진 것으로 주제를 바꿉니다 오픈 소스 커뮤니티와 오픈 소스를 통해 액세스할
and and thriving capabilities that you have access to through open source, you're going to get to know
수 있는 역량이 번창하는 것으로요 여러분은 당혹스러운 얼굴을 아주
hugging face really well, really, really well.
아주 잘 알게 될 거예요
You're going to work with pipelines and also with Tokenizers and with the models themselves with transformer
파이프라인도 작업하고 Tokenizers도 작업하고 트랜스포머 모델 그 자체도
models.
작업하죠
And ultimately you're going to be running inference of open source models using Google Colab on their
궁극적으로 여러분은 오픈 소스 모델을 실행할 겁니다 구글 Colab을 이용해 GPU와
boxes with GPUs.
함께 상자에서요
And so by the end of the week, you'll be highly proficient with inference of open source models.
주말쯤엔 오픈 소스 모델 추론에 아주 능숙해지실 거예요
And I can't wait to get to it.
빨리 get it로 가고 싶네요
And I will see you then.
그때 봐요